AMADEO ADVINCULA ESTUITA

Brgy. Palaypay, Basey, Samar 06720

Cell: 09058683461

DEOmeansGOD@gmail.com



Professional Summary

Great Shift Leader with a heavy background in the missionary, frontline service, and business industry, and dedicated and meticulous professional with seven months' progressive experience in clerical and entrepreneurship assistance arena, offers an outgoing personality and the ability to motivate a team of employees. Understands the importance of following management guidelines and task lists and has the ability to balance professional attitude while having fun; enjoys work in a fast paced environment. Has two years of experience supervising others while completing daily shifts.

Core Qualifications

- Civil-Service Professional Passer (March 2015)
- Civil-Service Sub-Professional Passer (October 2010)
- National Certificate Level II Holder for Computer Software
- Functional knowledge of reception duties and mail handling

- Experienced in Microsoft Office
- Internet Literate
- Shorthand Literate
- Proven ability to manage filing systems and scheduling activities
- Knowledge of assisting in planning and logistics of event planning
- Professional attitude and appearance

Experience

Department of Trade and Industry, Negosyo Center Tacloban **Negosyo Center Officer,** June 2016 – December 2016

- Accepted and facilitated all new registration and renewal application of MSMEs, including application for Barangay Micro-Business Enterprise (BMBE);
- Coordinated with the respective local government units (LGUs) and liaise with concerned government agencies to process the duly accomplished forms submitted by the MSMEs;
- Implemented a unified business registration process preferably through automated systems such as the Philippine Business Registry (PBR);
- Assisted MSMEs in meeting regulatory requirements to start and maintain the business;
- Built local support networks and establish market linkages for MSME development through the Micro, Small and Medium Enterprise Development (MSMED) Council and DTI;
- Facilitated access to grants and other forms of financial assistance, shared service facilities and equipment, and other support for MSMEs through national government agencies (NGAs);
- Ensured management guidance, assistance and improvement of the working conditions of MSMEs;
- Co-organized with the local chambers of commerce, other business organizations and government agencies, a mentoring program for prospective and current entrepreneurs and investors;
- Conducted other programs or projects for entrepreneurial development in the country aligned with the MSMEs development plan.
- Provided information and services in training, financing, marketing and other areas as may be required by MSMEs;

- Established and maintained a databank which will support business information requirements of MSMEs:
- Promoted ease of doing business and access to services for MSMEs within its jurisdiction;
- Supported private sector activities relating to MSMEs development;
- Encouraged government institutions that are related to the business application process to help promulgate information regarding the Negosyo Center;
- Coordinated with schools and related organizations on the development of youth entrepreneurship program;
- Encouraged women entrepreneurship through access to information, training, credit facilities, and other forms of assistance.
- Monitored and recommended business-process improvement for MSMEs;
- Established a feedback mechanism among the MSMEs in the respective jurisdiction of Negosyo Centers.

ABE International College of Business and Accountancy, Tacloban City **Part-time Instructor**. June 2016 – October 2016

- Taught courses in their subject area such as Entrepreneurship and Marketing
- Worked with students who are studying for a degree or are taking classes to improve their knowledge or career skills
- Developed an instructional plan (known as a course outline or syllabus) for the course(s) they teach and ensure that it meets college and department standards
- Planned lessons and assignments
- Worked with colleagues to develop or modify the curriculum for a degree or certificate program involving a series of courses
- Assessed students' progress by grading papers, tests, and other work
- Advised students about which classes to take and how to achieve their goals
- Conducted research and experiments to advance knowledge in their field

Eastern Visayas State University, Office of the Registrar **Student Assistant**, November 2014 – February 2015

- Helped the Administrative Assistant in answering the phones and greeting visitors to our office
- Trained new Student Assistant on processes and policies
- Assisted staff and students by providing accurate information regarding our office
- Performed varied clerical duties such as filing copying running errands answering the telephone and assisting students
- Prepared signs posters and mailings and assist with other tasks and projects as assigned
- Assisted the Administrative Assistant with the prompt processing and distribution of assignment letters

The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints, Philippines Quezon City North Mission Full-time Missionary, July 2011 – August 2013

- Supervised productivity of 140 full time representatives
- Presided over 35 training seminars/held 75 accountability interviews
- Acquired fluency in written and spoken Tagalog and English
- Designed spreadsheets to analyze statistics for 140 missionaries in various cities
- Time management, effective planning and goal setting
- Study and research habits
- Interpersonal communication: eye contact, body language, and the ability to carry on a conversation
- Conflict management, public speaking and ability to manage and oversee the work of others
- Working as part of a team, active listening, teaching English and foreign language

Education

Bachelor of Science in Entrepreneurship 2016, Leadership Awardee

Eastern Visayas State University, Tacloban City

Small Business Counselor's Course 2016

University of the Philippines, Institute for Small-Scale Industries

Associate of Science in Computer Science 2008, Second Honors

Eastern Visayas Technical College, Basey, Samar

Professional Affiliations

- Rotaract Club of EVSU
- Student Publication Office
- Gender and Development Youth Coordinators
- Voice of the Youth Tacloban Chapter
- Federation Pag-asa Youth Association of the Philippines
- Junior Asia Pacific Entrepreneur
- Student in Free Enterprise
- Traffick Jam IOM Tacloban

References

Mr. Arneil Defensor Aro, Principal III

Bignay National High School, Valenzuela City 09777955440

Mr. Severo L. Blanco II, MM

Eastern Visayas State University, Tacloban City 09278625768